# ANKUJ UNIYAL

 $+91~8527613728 \diamond Gurgaonn, Harvana, India$ 

ankujuniyal9797@gmail.com \leq linkedin.com/in/ankujuniyal \leq github

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Working as a DevOps engineer over 8 years focusing on cloud infrastructure, CI/CD pipelines and automation tools. I have a track record of enhancing efficiency and productivity by introducing solutions and fostering teamwork. I am deeply interested, in transformation and excited to apply my expertise to drive change.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Technology I.T, Uttarakhand Technical University, Dehradun

2009 - 2013

#### **SKILLS**

Platform OpenShift K8s, GCP, CDN (Akamai), Kafka (Confluent),

DevSecOps (Blackduck, Coverity, Sonarqube), ServiceMesh, Api Getway (Kong),

AWS, Docker, Git, JIRA

Apache Tomcat, Apache HTTP, Nginx, Weblogic Web/App Servers

Jenkins, Ansible, GoCD, Terrafrom Automation

Monitoring Prometheus, Grafana, Open telemetry, Elastic Stack (ELK), Zabbix

Programming Languages Python, Shell Scripting, Java (Basic) Database Mongo, Mysql, influx, Elasticserach Soft Skills Interpersonal, Teamwork, Leadership

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Sr. Devops Engineer

Jun 2021 - Present Gurugram, India

Bharti Airtel Ltd.

- Implementing Kafka data pipeline.
- Led the migration of Middleware, to Kubernetes.
- Implementing CDN/GTM rule on Akamai.
- Managing API gateway(Kong)
- Enhanced CI/CD process to deploy applications on various platforms.

#### Sr.Software Development Engineer

Jul 2017 - May 2021 (3 years 11 months)

Unify Technologies

Gurugram, India

- Automated Zabbix Monitoring 100% Infra using REST API, Python, and Flax skills.
- Led Kafka Deployment
- Integrated Kong API Gateway. Created customized plugins using Lua scripting to improve the functionality and efficiency of APIs.

### Linux System Administrator

Silverpush

Guruqram, India

Feb 2016 - Jan 2017 (1 year)

System Administrator

Oct 2013 - Feb 2016 (2 years 5 months)

Rapidsoft Technologies

Gurugram, India

### LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

• RHCE - Red Hat 150-183-291

• RHCSA - Red Hat 150-183-291

• Learning Docker LinkedIn